

www.heiux.com czarnecki.t@outlook.com +48 500 309 303

Work eligibility: EU (Polish citizen) China (family permit)

Tomasz Czarnecki a Senior Product Designer (UX/UI)





with an Intercultural Background

Personal Statement

A passionate **Product Designer (UX/UI)** and **Developer**, a **Problem Solver** with more than 7 years of overseas working experience.

Excellent algorithmic thinking and mission to create logical experiences combining user and business needs. Proven track record of intercultural work experience, including **project managing** roles.

Experienced in introducing, designing and maintaining **Design Systems**. Successfully increased user engagement and Heineken's Data Lake's health by adding **Gamification** into a corporate environment.

Fascinated by **Metaverse**, **Web3.0** and **Blockchain** technology. Able to contribute to your Digital Products since the research, ideation, through prototyping and high fidelity design phases.

Professional Experience

05.2021 - now 10 months

Senior Product Designer (UX & Gamification) • Heineken • Amsterdam, Netherlands Skills: gamification, game economy, design systems, prototyping, wireframing Tools: Figma, Adobe CC, Davinci Resolve

- Worked with BIG DATA & AI teams providing analytical solutions for Internal Users;
- Created an initial version of a Design System that increased product's coherence;
- · Introduced Gamification to increase Data Quality in the Heineken's Data Lake;
- Created a concept of a Gamified Solution that would spark bottom-up innovation;
- Applied intercultural proficiency to research users located on 6 continents;

02.2020 - 05.2021

1 year 4 month

Product Designer (UX/UI) • macopedia.com • Poznan, Poland

Skills: design systems, problem solving, design thinking, usability testing, prototyping Tools: Figma, Adobe CC, Jira, Odoo, Mattermost

- Standardised company's workflow by introducing a cohesive Design System;
- Transferred design workflow to cloud-based software Figma;
- Organised a series of Figma lectures for co-workers;
- Worked independently with clients across the European Union;
- Encouraged usage of Design Thinking methodology in the company's strategy;

05.2017 - 12.2019

2 years 8 month

Associate Designer | Team Lead • SEVEN International • Guizhou, China Skills: Chinese, management, leadership, working with tight deadlines, recruiting Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Lumion, Adobe InDesign/Photoshop

- Successfully led team of 10 Chinese-only speaking designers;
- Simultaneously managed teams located on 2 continents: in China and Poland;
- Provided conceptual designs for 4 Social Hosing projects and 5 local Banks;
- Led recruitment processes of 12 junior staff-members (for Polish office);
- Prepared series of Rhinoceros 3D courses (in Chinese office);
- Led client meetings and presentations for Chinese customers;

06.2016 - 05.2017

1 year

Parametric Designer • PWD Architecture • Beijing, China

Skills: sketching, research, concept design, working with tight deadlines Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Played a crucial role in winning 21 million m² Urban Planning competition;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by building an Urban Planning Library;
- Taught series of Grasshopper workshops for coworkers;
- Introduced parametric design methodology;

02.2015 - 06.2016

Parametric Designer • MAD Architects • Beijing, China

1 year 5 month Skills: parametric design, algorithmic thinking, genetic algorithms, optimisation Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Grasshopper, C# Scripting, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign

- Was the main architect and developer of a Scripting Library;
- Was a key member of the company's Parametric Research Group;
- Saved hundreds of working hours by providing complex parametric models;

01.2014 - 02.2015

1 year 2 months

Junior Architect • SEVEN International • Poznan, Poland and Guizhou, China Skills: Chinese, intercultural communication, management, concept design; Tools: Rhinoceros 3D, Adobe Illustrator/InDesign, AutoCAD

Provided conceptions of buildings that were later realized by Chinese team;

09.2013 - 01.2014

5 months

Construction Site Intern • Budnex Developer • Gorzow, Poland

Helped a construction site manager to supervise the quality of construction;

11.2012 - 05.2013

7 months

Interior Design Intern • Kaja Interieurs • Netherlands

• Supported senior designers in an office as well as on a site;

Formal Education

09.2014 - 04.2015

8 months

Building and Environment Ph.D. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

- 2 semesters of Ph.D. studies realized at Faculty of Civil Engineering;
- Focused on Parametric Design: Grasshopper, C#, Algorithmic Thinking;

09.2011 - 06.2012

10 months

Architecture Erasmus • Istanbul Technical University • Turkey • 2 semesters of international exchange;

03.2011 - 06.2014

3 years 4 months

Architecture M.Sc. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• Graduated with the highest A-grade;

09.2007 - 02.2011 3 years 6 months

09.2006 - 06.2007 10 months Architecture B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• Supervisor: prof. Ewa Pruszewicz-Sipińska, dean of the Architecture Faculty;

Computer Science B.Eng. • Poznan University of Technology • Poland

• 2 semesters of B.Eng. studies in English;

Skills and Tools

skills

- Problem solving
- Prototyping
- · Design thinking

Working under pressure

Information architecture

- Usability testing User research
- Management

tools

• Figma

- Adobe CC
- Teamwork React

Adobe XD

• Git

Javascript

• Jira

- Npm/Node.js
- CSS

· Odoo

Agile

• Html

languages

- English: C2
- Polish: Native
- Chinese: B2

Courses and Trainings

UX Design Masterclass • by Matt Hryhorsky

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design • by Rob Sutcliffe **UX Design & User Experience Design Course •** by Daniel Walter Scott User Experience Design - Adobe XD UI UX Design • by Daniel Walter Scott Responsive Web Design - HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap • by Daniel Walter Scott UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development • by Joe Natoli The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery • by Andrei Neagoie



www.heiux.com czarnecki.t@outlook.com +48 500 309 303

Tomasz Czarnecki a Senior Product Designer (UX/UI)



with an Intercultural Background

Cover Letter

Dear Team,

my name is Tomasz. I am a passionate **Product Designer (UX/UI)**, who can code. I am a **Problem Solver** with excellent algorithmic thinking skills and more than 7 years of **overseas working experience**. I am proficient with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jira, and GIT - currently learning React+Redux.

During these last years, I have had the chance to live and work in three different cultural backgrounds. I was born and raised in **Europe**, studied in the **Middle East**, and worked in **East Asia**. This unique cultural background taught me great respect for cultural diversity. I believe that every human being is unique and worth being listened to.

I have a strong professional background in **Design** and **Computer Science**. For most of my professional career, I was working as a hybrid designer-developer using Grasshopper 3D visual programming language with Rhino Common library (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grasshopper_3D). With my unique skill-set, I had a chance to contribute my time and talent to one of the most iconic buildings of the XXI century: **Harbin Opera House** in China (https://www.archdaily.com/778933/harbin-opera-house-mad-architects).

I am also a proficient Mandarin speaker. I had a chance to live and work for 5 years in China, where I grew and worked as a **Project Architect**. I successfully led projects, organized client presentations and design workshops - all in Chinese. I **managed** a team of Mandarin-only speakers to deliver high-quality designs within the deadlines.

I believe that the design process of every digital or physical product should be **user-oriented** - it is crucial for its success. But it also should be **business-centered** - as no product could exist without fulfilling its commercial goals.

For more information concerning my background, please take a look at "About Section" of my webpage: https://www.heiux.com/

or my LinkedIn profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tczarnecki/

If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to contact me. I am looking forward to hearing from you!

Best Regards,

Tomasz Czarnecki